Daniel Cox

Dartmouth, NS, Canada Phone: (902) 818 – 8129

Email: danielcox996@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/daniel-cox-b0320115b Website: https://dangerousdaniel.github.io/

PROFILE

I'm a second year IT Programming student at NSCC IT campus, graduating in September 2020. I had done serval group projects where I worked as a front-end developer for an online trading card game and lead a team of 7 junior developers for the IT Job Fair website. We were all worked on the front end and back end of the site.

I'm currently creating a 2D fantasy platform game named Vex Monsters, where you save monsters from evil betrayed. It is in the development stage, and I'm the Game Director. Where I create the story and programming the game mechanics and UI (User Interface) for the game.

EDUCATION

IT: Programming September 2018 – May 2020

NSCC IT Campus, Halifax, NS

Academic & Career Connections September 2017 – May 2018

NSCC IT Campus, Halifax, NS

Completed Math 12 and English 12.

Adult Learning Program September 2016 – June 2017

Dartmouth Learning Network, Dartmouth, NS

• Skills development in math.

High School Diploma

Prince Andrew High School, Dartmouth, NS

September 2014 – June 2015

1

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Developer

November 2019 – March 2020

Nova Scotia Community College, Halifax, NS

- Overseeing a team of 7 junior developers in handling various development tasks in support of Project Blackbird. The scope of work ranges from front end to back end, quality control through GitHub of completed work, plus various front end tasks.
- The platform we are using is Laravel.
- · Worked in the front-end and back-end in HTML, CSS and PHP
- Website: bbird.org

Line Cook

November 2018 – March 2020

Dairy Queen, Dartmouth, NS

- Successfully completed food safety training
- Food preparation
- Cooked food on the grill and deep fryer
- Responsible for cleaning the kitchen

Junior Developer

April 2019 – May 2019

Nova Scotia Community College, Halifax, NS

As a junior developer, I assisted in developing an online trading card game. My
role focused on developing the home page, Player's page, as well as
incorporating responsive design into the site. This involved using HTML and CSS
to create the website. The team used GitHub to assign tasks.

Dishwasher

July 2016 – November 2018

Swiss Chalet, Dartmouth, NS

- Keep up a fast pace during rush hours to ensure adequate dishes were clean.
- Provide my employer with a flexible schedule, which allowed me to go in to work on short notice.
- Maintain a neat and tidy workplace to ensure health and safety standards were met.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Team Coordinator

September 2019 – March 2020

NSCC IT Job Fair & Conference- 2020, Dartmouth, NS

 Responsible for helping managed the team by tracking team minutes, participating in meetings, being a part of the leadership group and helping track loose ends.

IT Technician May 2017 - Present

Dartmouth Learning Network, Dartmouth, NS

- Diagnose computer problems, monitor computer processing systems, install software and perform tests on computer equipment and programs.
- Set up computer equipment, schedule maintenance and teach clients to use programs.
- Perform computer repairs and computer parts ordering.
- Maintain an inventory of over 40 computers.

Computer Basics Instructor Assistant

September 2017 – June 2018

Dartmouth Learning Network, Dartmouth, NS

- Taught seniors and young adults essential computer skills, such as how to send emails, how to type, how to use a mouse, and how to explore the internet.
- Set up computers with Windows and other software required for the company's workplace. I kept all the computers and the laptops organized for them.

Classroom Tutor

July 2017 August 2017

Dartmouth Learning Network, Dartmouth, NS

- Supported all adults attending literacy upgrading class with classwork.
- Assisted students with disabilities on field trips.
- Provided information technology assistance to the instructor and supported students with their computers use.

Volunteer Facilitator

January 2017 - May 2017

Dartmouth Learning Network, Dartmouth, NS

- Participated in a facilitator training program focused on raising gambling harm awareness.
- Facilitated gambling harm awareness workshop across Nova Scotia.
- Oversaw all the team's technical needs.
- Demonstrated strong organization and teamwork skills.

Sales Clerk

September 2015 – June 2016

Common Values and Mort's Convenience, Dartmouth, NS

- Processed purchases and kept accurate records of daily sales.
- Conducted monthly product inventory to allow sufficient stock to be ordered for the next month.
- Ensured a tidy and safe work environment by completing a daily cleaning list.

MAMBEC Senior Instructor

March 2014 - June 2015

Martial Art Mind-Body Education Centre (MAMBEC), Dartmouth, NS

- Trained children in Martial Arts and self-discipline.
- Worked year-round on weekends, school professional development days and summer vacation.
- Completed over 500 Leadership/Volunteer hours.

ADDITIONAL TRAINING & ACHIEVEMENTS

•	Challenge NS 2017 Second Place	2017
•	Occupational Health & Safety - NSCC	2017
•	WHMIS 2015 - NSCC	2017
•	MAMBEC Martial Art Black Belt	2012